KRISTEN CADACIO

kriscadacio@gmail.com | 347.452.3910 New York, New York

Github | LinkedIn | Medium

Software engineer with solid foundations in frontend and backend technologies. With ten years of professional experience in the television industry, I successfully managed teams, created hours of content, and managed project life cycles from acquisition to customer delivery for various production companies. I'm a voracious learner who is excited to utilize my newfound passion and skills to develop and create exciting products.

SKILLS

• JavaScript • HTML • CSS • React.js • Ruby on Rails • SQL • Git • Figma • Trello • Avid • Miro

PROJECTS

ReciPrep | Github | Demo

An application for users to add recipes and use those recipes to meal prep for the week

- · Applied React to build out the user interface and Ruby on Rails to store and retrieve user's data
- Utilized MVC architectural pattern using RESTful API for seamless CRUD functionality, allowing users to update recipe information and move recipes from one column list to another
- Implemented Cloudinary CDN to enable cloud storage of user image uploads
- Built a kanban style interface utilizing React DnD library allowing users to drag and drop their meals from one day to another in order to meal prep for the week

BookBook | Github | Demo

An application that allows users to search for books and organize them into lists

- Utilized Google's Book API so users can search for a wide range of book titles and store them into organized lists
- · Achieved seamless real-time CRUD functionality with RESTful API, where users can create and edit book lists
- Implemented user login and registration using Ruby gems: Bcrypt and Rack-Cors
- Used modals, CSS flexbox, and carousels with vanilla CSS for an appealing and organized design

Swap't | Frontend-Github | Backend-Github | Demo

An application where users can upload items and search for items they want to exchange with other users

- Built an API back-end using Ruby, Sinatra, and React that has full CRUD functionalities
- · Implemented CSS grid for a clean and minimalistic style
- · Designed the web page layout utilizing Miro

EXPERIENCE

Post Manager | Red Marble Media / A+E Networks / Weinberger Media

Jan 2019 - Feb 2022

- Created and maintained edit schedules to meet internal and network deadlines
- Coordinated cross-functional teams for successful progression from production to post-production phases
- Oversaw the workflow and priorities of editors and assistant editors to ensure the team was on schedule for ontime delivery of show deliverables to the network

Associate / Post Producer | Hot Snakes / Big Fish / Left Right Productions

Aug 2014 - Dec 2019

- Pioneered creative solutions for storyline inconsistencies and character flaws in order to meet network requirements and creative vision
- Collaborated with editors and executives on 2-3 episodes concurrently to develop and execute entertaining storylines and characters
- Worked with post supervisors and coordinators to ensure workflow efficiency by prioritizing ingest requests and delegating tasks to AE's and associate producers
- · Media managed volumes of footage, archival, and third-party materials for editors and producers

Office Manager | Left Right Productions

March 2012 - April 2014

- Oversaw daily operations for an office employing 200 staff and freelance employees
- Managed a budget of 10K for daily office expenses, maintenance, and social activities
- · Negotiated vendor contracts and implemented cost-saving strategies

EDUCATION